Kairsten Fay

Full Stack Software Developer kairsten.fay@gmail.com
Seattle, WA

GitHub: github.com/kairstenfay **Portfolio**: kairstenfay.github.io/projects **LinkedIn**: linkedin.com/in/kairsten-fay **Google Scholar**: bit.ly/2G4jqCp

Software developer experienced in writing data pipelines, infrastructure code, and front-end applications in fast-paced research environments with open source contributions and 10+ publications emphasizing my skills.

SKILLS

Python, JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Git, React (JS/Native), Shell (Bash), LaTeX, HTML5/CSS, D3, Docker, Flask, Node.js, Expo

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fred Hutch Cancer Research Center, Seattle, WA

Apr 2019 - present

Full stack software developer

github.com/seattleflu

- Built the data warehouse, ETL pipelines, and reporting systems for the Seattle Flu Study, enabling free, community, COVID-19 testing for 18,000+ participants to date.
- Wrote and deployed full-stack applications for public and internal use, automating away tasks that collectively saved company employees hundreds of hours per month.
- Integrated with various APIs (AWS, Slack, Mapbox) and used existing tools wherever possible to deliver results quickly and efficiently.
- Onboarded and trained new hires, relying heavily on the extensive documentation effort I led to comprehensively describe our internal tools and practices.

University of Washington IHME, Seattle, WA

Oct 2018 – Apr 2019

Full stack web developer

- Refactored codebase to reduce complexity and replaced thousands of lines of legacy code.
- Improved usability of internal tools to delight customers by speeding up processing times and by gathering and implementing stories for a better user experience.

University of Washington IHME, Seattle, WA

Feb 2017 – Oct 2018

Data analyst

- Developed a machine learning framework in scikit-learn using random forest and XGBoost algorithms, subsequently unifying the delivery of and accuracy of results by 50-100%.
- Improved the ETL pipeline code to prevent data loss. Reduced manual data extraction time by 20%, saving hundreds of hours of data analyst time.

EDUCATION